Okay, Raj.
好了 Raj
Hand me the #6 Torx screwdriver.
给我6号内六角螺丝起子
Stop.
停
We can't do this. It's not right.
我们不能这样做 这是不对的
Sheldon, you have two choices.
Sheldon 你有两种选择
ther you let him put a
bigger hard drive in the TiVo,
要么你让他给TiVo换个大点的硬盘
or you delete stuff
before we go out of town.
要么在我们离城前删点东西
But once you open the box,
you've voided the warranty.
但是打开机器 就享受不了质保了
The warranty is a sacred covenant we've
entered into with the manufacturer.
质保协议是我们和厂家签订的重要协议
He offers to stand by his
equipment, and we in return
厂家对他们产品提供质保 而我们
agree not to violate the
integrity of the internal hardware.
要做到不人为破坏内部硬件
This little orange sticker is all
that stands between us and anarchy.
我们和烂摊子之前可就这
小黄贴纸之隔啊
Okay, then we won't
touch the hard drive.
好吧 我们不动硬盘
We'll just erase the
first season of Battlestar.
把第一季太空堡垒卡拉狄加删了就行
There. We're outlaws.
没质保了
Here you go, Leonard. Is
this going to be big enough?
Leonard 给你 这够用吧?
It's perfect.
棒极了
For taking daffodils to your unicorn.
给你独角兽装水仙花用?
It's just for my
notebooks. Thanks, Penny.
放我的笔记本 谢了 Penny
I love San Francisco. I
wish I was going with you.
我超喜欢旧金山 要能一起去就好了
I understand your envy.
Thiss a can't-miss symposium.
你当然会羡慕了
这场研讨会可是百年一遇
There are going to be discussions on
bioorganic cellular computer devices,
会讨论生物有机细胞计算机设备
the advancements in
multi-threaded task completion,
多线程任务完成方面的进展
plus a roundtable on the
nonequilibrium Green's function approach
还有一个非平衡性格林函数在
to the photoionization process in atoms.
原子光电离进程中运用的圆桌会议
When I go, I usually just get
hammered and ride the cable cars.
我去那 通常是大醉一场还有坐坐缆车
This conference is kind of a big thing.
这次会议真是非比寻常
The keynote address is being
delivered by George Smoot.
主讲人可是George Smoot
Oh, my God, the George Smoot?
哦 上帝 那George Smoot?
- You've heard of him?
- Of course I haven't.
- 你听过?
- 当然没有
George Smoot is a Nobel Prize-winning
physicist, one of the great minds of our time.
George Smoot是物理学诺贝尔奖获得者
是当今著名的学者
His work in black body form and anisotropy
of the cosmic microwave background radiation
他对于宇宙微波背景辐射的黑体
和各向异性研究
cemented our understanding
of the origin of the universe.
巩固了我们对宇宙起源的了解
It's kind of a funny
name, though-- "Smoot."
名字念起来倒挺有趣 Smoot
It's like talking to a chimp.
简直是跟大猩猩说话
Okay, now that I've been completely
insulted, have a good flight.
得 伤自尊了 你们飞行愉快吧
Yeah, I wish.
我倒是想飞
We're not flying.
We're taking the train.
但我们不坐飞机 我们搭火车
Oh, cool.
哦 酷
Yeah, cool. Seven times as long as
flying, and costs almost twice as much.
是很酷 不仅时间是乘飞机的7倍
连车票都贵上一倍呢
Well, then why are you doing it?
那么你们干嘛还坐火车?
Well, we had a vote. Three
of us voted for airplane.
我们投票来着 3票坐飞机
Sheldon voted for train.
So we're taking the trn.
Sheldon投坐火车 所以我们坐火车
Don't say it like that, Leonard.
别用这腔调说 Leonard
Say it like: We're taking the train!
应该是 我们坐火车~~!
荣誉出品
翻译: Thera 奕鹂 penny
校对: penny
时间轴: 咔肉肉
Hey, we're all going over to the Apple store
to make fun of the guys at the Genius Bar.
我们要去苹果专卖店
作弄那些天才吧的家伙
You want to come?
你来吗?
Oh, I always enjoy that,
but I'm a little busy.
我是很想去啦 不过现在有点忙
What are you doing?
你忙啥呢?
I'm simplifying the task
of packing for our trip.
我在为旅行打包做简化工作
See, by attaching RFID tags to my
clothing, it will able my laptop
给衣服贴上电子标签
这样用上这个扫描器就可以
to read and identify
the items with this wand.
让电脑来识别物品了
I will then cross-reference them against
destination, anticipated activity spectrum,
然后我再根据目的地 预计活动频谱
weather conditions,
duration of trip, et cetera.
天气状况 旅行时间等信息来相互对照
Well, that does sound much simpler.
呃 听起来是挺简化的
How long is this going to take?
那你要弄多久?
Assuming I can keep up this
pace, three hours, 11 minutes,
照我现在的速度 大约3小时11分钟
and plus however long tak to conclude
this fairly pointless conversation.
再加上不知道多久才能结束这
毫无意义的对话
Teasing the guys at the Apple
store seems a little redundant now.
看来作弄苹果店里的人都多余
- I don't follow.
- I wouldn't expect you to. I'll see you later.
- 我没明白
- 也没指望你明白 待会见
Socks:one pair, cotton, argyle, blue.
袜子 一双 棉质 菱形花纹 蓝色
Socks: one pair, cotton, argyle, blue.
What on earth are you doing?
你这是要干嘛?
Whatever it is, I'm guessing
we're doing it wrong.
不管我做了什么 我猜我是做错了
Gentlemen, this is the Coast Starlight,
先生们 这可是海岸星光列车
one of the great American trains operating
on one of the classic American routes.
美国经典路线上的最好列车之一
On this side, you'll see panoramic ocean vistas
inaccessible to any other form of transportation,
坐这边 可以享受乘坐其他交通工具
所无法体会的全景式海岸风光
while on your side, you'll be
treated to 350 miles of CostCos,
坐这边呢 看到的是350英里的好市多
Jiffy Lubes, and cinderblock
homes with above-ground pools.
捷飞络连锁店 还有带泳池水泥民居
Come on, Raj.
这儿 Raj
What's wrong with Jiffy Lubes?
捷飞络有啥不好的?
No.
不
- Why not?
- That's over the wheelbase.
- 又怎么啦?
- 这座位正好在轴距上
Are you completely unfamiliar
with the suspension characteristics
你难道一点不清楚
80年代前所造豪华乘坐席
of a pre-1980 Pullman-built
Superliner Deluxe passenger coach?
悬挂系统的特性吗?
Sheldon, we've been on
this train 90 seconds,
Sheldon 才上车90秒
and you've already
said a thousand words.
你已经叽歪了上千句了
Just tell us where to sit and shut up.
你直接说坐哪 然后闭嘴
Here.
这儿
I'm hoping once you reap the endorphic rewards of the
steady clickety-clack of steel wheels on polished rails,
我希望你在享受车轮
和铁轨发出的美妙喀嚓声时
your sour disposition will abate.
你的抱怨会少一点
Yeah, maybe.
可能
Meanwhil back in the 21st century,
people are raising their tray tables
同时21世纪的人
在准备收起折叠桌
and putting their seat-backs in an upright
position 'cause it's time to land in San Francisco.
将座椅调整到竖直状态
因为飞机要着陆到旧金山了
It's not so bad, really.
其实也没那么糟啦
At least these trains
have modern plumbing.
至少这火车有现代化的卫生间
In India, you squat over a hole in the
train and expose your naked buttocks
在印度 你得光着屁屁
蹲在车厢里的一个洞上
to the chilly air of Rajasthan.
感受拉贾斯坦邦的冷空气
He is referring, of course, to third class on
Indian Railways' magnificent Ranakpur Express
他说的当然是印度
华丽的Ranakpur特快三等席
and its 1,200-kilometer journey from
Maharashtra to the Bikaner Junction.
从马哈拉施特拉邦到比卡内尔接轨点
的1200公里旅途
Oh, look, now he's boring
on an international scale.
哦 现在他又开始罗嗦国际单位了
Holy crap! Look!
哦 我的天! 看哪!
Is that who I think it is?
不会真是她吧?
It can't be. What would Summer
Glau be doing riding the train?
不能够啊 Summer Glau干嘛坐火车
Maybe John Connor's aboard and she's
protecting him from an evil Terminator.
可能John Connor也在车上
她要保护他不被坏终结者追杀
Unlikely. That's a
television show, Leonard.
不太可能 那只是电视剧啦 Leonard
Thank you.
多谢提醒
Of course, if SkyNet actually
did exist in the future,
当然啦 如果"天网"真的存在于未来世界
a perfect way to infiltrate and destroy
mankind would be to send Terminators back posing
那么完美潜入毁灭人类的方法就是
让派来的终结者
as actors who have played Terminators
in popular films and television series,
扮成曾在热门电影剧集中
饰演过终结者的演员
lulling us into a false
sense of security, i.e.,
让我们产生安全错觉 就像是
"That's Summer Glau "from
The Sarah Connor Chronicles.
"她是里的Summer Glau"
No, Summer, don't kill
me!" I'm pro-robot! Ahh!"
- 不要 Summer 别杀我!
- "我是机器人!啊!"
At least he's off the train crap.
至少他不再纠结那些火车的废话了
Whee!
嘻嘻!
Sheldon, I owe you an apology.
Sheldon 我得向你道歉
Taking the train was
a stroke of brilliance!
乘火车绝对是次天才的举动!
I've actually got a
shot at a Terminator.
终于有机会接触终结者了
Oh, please.When it comes to Terminators,
拜托 谈到终结者
you've got a better shot of
scoring with Arnold Schwarzenegger.
我看你还是和施瓦辛格机会比较大
You're overlooking something.
你忽略了件事
I have 11 hours with
her in a confined space.
我将和她在这个狭窄的空间里
待上11个小时
Unless she's willing to jump off a moving
train, tuck and roll down the side of a hill,
除非她愿意跳下行驶的火车
翻转着滚下那边的山坡
she will eventually succumb to the
acquired taste that is ward Wolowitz.
她最终将屈服于逐渐产生好感的对象
那就是我 Howard Wolowitz
My money's on tuck and roll.
我压她滚下山
I'm confused.
我搞不懂了
I thought you were involved in some sort of
socially intimate pairing with Leslie Winkle.
我以为你和Leslie Winkle在社交上
保持着某种亲密关系
- Sheldon, let me explain to you how this works.
- All right.
- Sheldon 我来给你解释下
- 好吧
- That's Summer Glau.
- Yes.
- 那是Summer Glau耶!
- 是啊
That's it.
就这理由
Hang on a sec. Why do you
get first crack at her?
等等 凭什么是你第一个去追她?
Um, well, let's see, couple
reasons. One, I saw her first.
呃 我想想 几个理由
第一 我先看到她的
No, you didn't. I did.
不 不是你 是我
Fair enough. But... then,
let me move on to #2.
那好吧 但是...我们说第二个理由吧
Unlike you, I can actually
talk to women when I'm sober.
和你不同 我能镇静地同一位女性交谈
You fail to take into account that
even mute, I am foreign and exotic,
你没有考虑到 即使不说话
我来自国外 有异国情调
while you, on the other
hand, are frail and pasty.
相反 而你呢 虚弱而苍白
Well, you know the old saying,
Pasty and frail never fail.
你知道有句老话吗
"虚弱苍白者从不失手"
Excuse me, but what about me?
打断一下 那还有我呢?
Why don't I get a shot?
咋没我的事了?
Fine, go ahead. Take a shot.
好吧 那你去啊 去碰碰运气
You know, I've already got a gorgeous
blonde back home at I can't score with.
家里已经有个搞不定的
漂亮金发妞儿了
I think I'll let you two take this one.
这一个还是留给你们俩吧
Sheldon, is there a place
on this train to get alcohol?
Sheldon 这火车上有地方卖酒吗?
Interesting that you ask.
你问起来我就讲讲
The Coast Starlight recently added
the refurbished Pacific Parlour Car.
海岸星光列车最近加入了
重新装修的"太平洋特等客车"
Built in 1956 and originally
known as the Santa Fe Lounge Car,
建于1956年 即著名的原"圣达菲休闲客车"
- the lower level is a theater and
the upper level - Yeah-yeah, which way?
- 下层是一个小剧院 上层是...
- 好的好的 怎么走?
is a bar that offers wine tastings
if you're going as far as Portland.
一个提供葡萄酒品尝的酒吧 快去吧
So aren't you going to go talk to her?
你不去找她搭讪?
I will, I'm just working
on my opening line.
我去 只是先酝酿下我的开场白
She's probably heard every
possible line, Howard.
她也许听腻了各种开场白 Howard
Why don't you just try "hello"?
你干嘛不直接说"你好"?
No, no, no, that
always creeps girls out.
不 不行 那句通常会把姑娘们吓跑
I need to come up with something that's
funny, smart and delicately suggests
我得想出一句
既风趣聪明又能微妙地暗示出
that my sexual endowment is
disproportionate to my physical stature.
我的做爱本领和我的身材不成正比
You're going to need more than 11 hours.
那11小时看来不够了
Oh, no.
噢 不
What's the matter?
怎么回事?
I forgot my flash drive.
我忘了带我的闪存卡
- So?
- So we have to go back.
- 那又怎样?
- 那我们就得回去
Okay, Sheldon, I'm going to say "why" and your
answer cannot be because I forgot my flash drive.
好吧 Sheldon 我接下来要问你为什么
你不能回答因为忘了带闪存卡
You don't understand.
你不明白
My flash drive has my paper on astrophysical
probes of M-theory effects in the early universe
我的闪存里存着我关于早期宇宙中
天体探测M理论效应的论文
that I was going to give to
George Smoot at the conference.
我打算在研讨会上给George Smoot看的
Why do you have to give
your paper to George Smoot?
你干嘛要把你的论文给George Smoot?
It's brilliant. He needs to read it.
太有才了 他应该阅读才对
So you'll send him an
e-mail when we get back.
那等我们回去 你给他发封邮件就行了
Then I won't get to see his
face light up as he reads it.
那我就看不到 他读到我论文时
神采奕奕的样子了
Right. Of course.
对 当然
Oh, this is an unmitigated disaster.
哦 这绝对是场灾难
Well, there's nothing you
can do about it, so relax.
你也没办法啊 放松点吧
Sit back, enjoy the clickety-clack of
the steel wheels on the polished rails.
坐好 享受火车钢轮在磨光的铁轨上
擦出的咔嗒咔嗒之声
You forgot your flash drive
你忘了带你的闪存
你忘了带你的闪存...
Only ten hours, 55 minutes to go.
再熬10小时55分钟就好了
It's hot in here. Must be Summer.
这儿真热 一定是夏天了
(Summer Glau的名有"夏天"之意)
So... where you gals headed?
这个...姑娘们上哪儿去?
Okay, I've found the perfect solution.
好了 我找到了完美的解决方案
We get off the train at
the next stop in Oxnard.
我们在下一站Oxnard站下车
We then take the 1:13
train back to Union Station.
然后乘1:13的火车到联合车站(洛杉矶)
We take a cab back to the apartment, get my
flash drive, and then race to San Luis Obispo,
搭计程车回公寓 拿上我的闪存卡
再迅速赶到San Luis Obispo
where, assuming the lights are with us
and minimal traffic, we'll meet the train.
如果天还没黑 没什么堵车的话
我们就能在那儿赶上火车
I've got a better idea.
我有个更好的主意
Are you going to be sarcastic?
你是想讽刺我吗?
Boy, you take all the
fun out of it for me.
孩子 你把我仅有的一点乐趣都剥夺了
Look, Penny's home. Why don't we just
call her, have her go in the apartment,
听着 Penny在家 我们何不打给她
让她去我们公寓
get your flash drive
and e-mail you the paper?
拿你的闪存卡
然后把论文发邮件给我们呢
- But the flash drive is in a locked drawer in my desk.
- So?
- 可闪存卡在我锁着的抽屉里啊
- 那又怎样?
- The key is hidden in my room.
- So?
- 钥匙藏在我的房间里啊
- 那又怎样?
- Penny would have to go into my room.
- So?
- Penny得进我的房间啊
- 那又怎样?
People don't go in my room!
任何人不允许进我的房间啊!
I see. Well, it seems once again, you're
caught between a rock and a crazy place.
明白了 看来你又一次进退两难了
Oh, I te when that happens.
哦 我真讨厌这种情况
It's hot in here. It must be Summer.
这儿真热 一定是夏天了
It's hot in here. Must be Summer.
- That's cute.
- Really? I just made it up.
- 真有趣
- 是吗? 我刚刚自己编的
Have you seen Slumdog Millionaire?
你看过吗?
Oh, yeah, I loved it.
看过啊 我爱死这部电影了
It's loosely based on my life.
大体上是根据我的经历改编的
Yeah, we're putting the play on for one night
in this little 99-seat theater. Can you come?
是啊 我们的剧要在
99座的小剧院上演一晚 你能来吗?
Oh, great.
噢 好极了
Do you know 98 other people
that might want to come?
知道哪98个人也愿意来吗?
Oh, hang on.
哦 等一下
- Hello?
- Listen carefully.
- 喂?
- 仔细听好
I'm about to give you a set of instructions,
which you must follow to the letter.
我要告诉你一系列指示
你必须严格按照指示做
Just a sec.
等一下
The theater is above a bowling
alley, so it's a little noisy,
剧院在一个保龄球球道上面
所以有点嘈杂
but it might be the only chance
I'll ever get to play Anne Frank.
但这可能是我饰演
安妮・弗兰克的唯一机会了
And the director is brilliant.
而且导演太有才了
He uses the bowling sounds
as, like, Nazi artillery.
他利用楼下保龄球的声音作
纳粹炮火声的音效
Okay, great, I'll see you then. Hello?
好吧 太好啦 那到时见咯 喂?
Okay, step four.
好 第四步
Do you see that small
plastic case on my dresser?
你看见我梳妆台上的小塑料盒了吗?
Your dresser? Who is this?
你的梳妆台?你是谁啊?
It's Sheldon.
Sheldon
Oh, hey, Sheldon! How is San Francisco?
嗨 Sheldon? 旧金山怎么样?
I'm not in San Francisco. I'm on a
train. Were you even listening to me?
我不在旧金山 我在火车上呢
你刚才没有在听吗?
Uh, no, I was talking to
my friend, but what's up?
没有 我在和朋友聊天 你有什么事?
What's up? I'll tell you what's up.
什么事? 我来告诉你怎么回事
I'm in a crisis situation, and I need you
to marshal your powers of concentration,
我陷入危急情况 我需要你集中精力
- limited as they may be...
- Give me the phone.
- 集中到...
- 把手机给我
Hi, Penny. It's Leonard.
嗨 Penny 我是Leonard
Hey, Leonard. What's
going on with Dr. Wkadood?
嘿 Leonard
怪里怪气博士怎么了?
He's calling to ask you a favor.
他打电话请你帮忙
You might be confused because he didn't use the
words, Penny, "Sheldon," "please" or "favor."
估计你没搞明白 因为他没说
"Penny" "Sheldon" "请" "帮忙"
Okay. Enough chitchat.
好了 别聊天了
Okay, step one. Locate your
emergency key to our apartment.
好 第一步 将你的紧急备用钥匙
插入我们公寓大门
Step two: enter our
apartment. Step three:...
第二步 进入我们的公寓
第三步...
Enter my broom.
进入我的卧室
- Oh, hang on, Sheldon, getting another call.
- No!
- 等等 Sheldon 有电话来了
- 不!
Leonard, let me tell you something.
Personal robots cannot get here soon enough.
Leonard 我告诉你
私人机器人没那么快到达这里
And that bright little star
peeking her head out early today...
而那颗清晨偷偷探出头一瞥的闪亮星星
that's Venus.
就是金星
(亦有爱神"维纳斯"之意)
That is so cool.
太酷了
You really know a lot about space.
你真的很了解太空
Come on. When you were on TV in
Firefly, you were actually in space.
拜托 你在电视上演时
你实际上就是在太空上
You're not one of those guys
who really believe that, are you?
你不是真的相信吧?
You mean one of the hopeless geeks? No.
你是说那些绝望的怪家伙?才不是
Those are crazy people.
那是群疯子
Howard, be a dear and get
me another one of these.
Howard 行行好 帮我再拿一杯这个
Now, him, he's one of those geeks.
看他 他就是怪家伙之一
All right, now, before you
enter my bedroom unescorted,
好吧 现在 在你独自进入我的卧室前
I need you to understand that this onetime grant
of access does not create a permanent easement.
我需要你弄清楚
一次进入许可并不代表永久通行权
Easement.
通-行-权
It's a legal right
of access. Good grief.
是合法进入权 老天爷啊
What? No, don't put me on hold.
什么? 别啊 别让我再等了
Do you believe him?
能相信吗
Normally around women, he has the
personality of a boiled potato.
一般一见女人 他就跟蔫豆角一样
Put one beer in him, and
he's M. Night Charmalarmalon.
一杯啤酒下了肚
立马变成魅力先生了
Is that what he's drinking?
It's not even real beer.
他就喝的这个? 根本都不算是酒啊
- What? - Look at it.
Non-alcoholic beer.
- 什么?
- 看啊 无酒精
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
- 怎么回事?
- 不知道
Some sort of placebo effect, I guess.
算是安慰剂效应吧
Placebo, you say. Interesting.
安慰剂是吧 有意思了
Yes, I'm still here. Where
am I going? I'm on a train.
是啊 当然在 还能去哪?
我可是在火车上
Now, what you'll be looking for is a small
wooden box located between a Hoberman's sphere
现在 在霍伯曼球面和
有黄铁矿斑点的石英样本中
and a sample of quartz
flecked with pyrite.
找一个木质的小盒子
Hoberman's Sphere.
霍伯曼球面
It's collapsible icosidodecahedron.
是个可折叠的三十二面体
No, the thing with the time
on it is my alarm clock.
不是 上面有时间的是我的闹表
Actually, in India, the names
of constellations are different.
实际在印度 星座的名字是不一样的
Where you have the Big Dipper,
we have the Big Curry Pot.
你们说北斗七星是大勺子
我们叫大咖喱锅
You're making that up.
你瞎编的
You got me.
被你拆穿了
Now what are you going to do with me?
现在打算怎么惩罚我?
- Raj.
- Yes?
- Raj
- 啥事?
- Look.
- What am I looking at?
- 瞧瞧
- 瞧什么?
You tell me.
你说呢
Non-alcoholic beer.
无酒精啤酒...
I'm the small package
good things come in.
我是完美事物的小小化身
Okay, I got a box, but
there's no key in here.
我是找到盒子了 但没有钥匙
Just letters.
都是信
That's the wrg box. Put it back.
拿错盒子了 放回去
Oh, Sheldon, are these
letters from your grandmother?
哦 Sheldon 都是你外婆寄的信?
Don't read those letters!
表读那些信哦!
Oh, look, she calls you
"Moon Pie." That is so cute.
呀 瞧瞧 她叫你"月亮派" 多可爱啊
Put down the letters!
快把信放下!
Hey, Penny. It's Leonard.
嘿 Penny 我是Leonard
Hey, Leonard. How's the train ride?
嘿Leonard 火车旅途怎么样?
Delightful.
很开心
Listen, I don't know what
you're doing right now,
听着 不知道你在读啥
but there are little bubbles forming
on the corners of Sheldon's mouth.
不过Sheldon气得嘴角吐泡了
Okay, yeah, I kind of crossed
a line. Put him back on.
好啦 我是越界了 让他接吧
Thank you.
谢谢
- I'm back.
- What up, Moon Pie?
- 我来了
- 咋样 月亮派?
Nobody calls me Moon Pie but Meemaw!
除了外婆 谁都不许叫我月亮派
Hey, Penny. Leonard again.
嘿 Penny 又是我Leonard
So anyway, in the dream, you and I
were ice skating, just the two of us.
总之 在梦里 我俩滑冰来着
就我们两个人
And then, I picked you up by your
ankles and twirled you round and round
然后我拖起你脚踝转啊转
until your legs tore off.
直到你的腿掉下来
I tried to stick them back
on, but before I could,
我尝试把它们接回去的 但还没来得及
you turned into a giant
loaf of pumpernickel bread.
你就变成一大块粗麦面包了
What do you think that means?
你觉得这是啥意思?
I really don't know.
我还真不知道
I'll give you a little
clue. My favorite sandwich?
给你点提示吧 我最爱的三明治?
Salami on pumpernickel.
粗麦面包夹意大利香肠
Is that so?
这样哦?
And did you know the word "pumpernickel" comes
from the German words "pumper" and "nickel,"
你知不知道粗麦面包(pumpernickel)是由
德文里的"pumper"和"nickel"来的
which loosely translates
to "fart goblin"?
可以大致译成"小笨蛋"?
No. I didn't.
不 不知道
Okay, I found the box. Now what?
好了 找到盒子里 接下来呢?
You're holding a Japanese puzzle box,
which takes ten precise moves to open.
你拿着的是日本解谜盒子
要走精确地十步才能打开
First, locate the panel
with the diamond pattern
首先 用钻石图案找到嵌板
and slide the center portion
one millimeter to the left.
将中间部分向左移动一毫米
Then, on the opposite end of the box,
slide the entire panel down two millimeters.
然后 在盒子的背面
将整个嵌板向下滑动两毫米
- You'll hear a slight click.
- Hang on.
- 你会听到咔哒一声
- 等等
Sheldon, do you have any
emotional attachment to this box?
Sheldon 你对这盒子有啥特殊感情吗?
No, it's a velty I ordered off the
Internet. Did you hear the click?
没 是我在网上买的新奇玩意
听到咔哒声没有?
Not yet.
还没
There it is.
有了
Okay, here's another one.
好 还有一个
If you married the famous rock guitarist
Johnny Winter, you'd be Summer Winter.
要是你嫁给著名摇滚吉他手
Johnny Winter 你就叫Summer Winter了
(夏天冬天)
Okay, I'm going to just go for
broke here and say I like you.
好了 跟你直说吧 我喜欢你
Yeah?
是吗?
So here's my question: do you
realistically see any conversational path
我想问问 你看有没啥可能
咱俩聊着聊着 就从现在的尴尬对话
that would take me from where
we are right now to a place
过渡到我约你出去 然后你说好的?
No.
没有
Fair enough. I'll leave you in peace.
很好 我不打扰你了
Thank you.
谢谢
But before I go,
我走之前呢
would you mind if I just take one picture
of us together for my Facebook page?
介不介意咱俩合个影
我好放到我Facebook上去?
Sure.
拍吧
Okay. Great. Now, can I take one
where it looks like we're making out?
好的 太棒了 能不能再拍张
看起来像是在亲热的?
Okay, now you're going to insert
the flash drive into the USB port...
好了 现在把闪存卡插到USB口...
She calls me Moon Pie because I'm
nummy-nummy and she could just eat me up.
她叫我月亮派 是因为我太口耐
她想把我吃掉
Now, please put the flash
drive in the USB port.
拜托了 把闪存卡插到USB口
The one that looks like
a little duck's mouth.
长的像鸭子嘴巴的
Hey, how'd it go?
嘿 怎么样?
Terminator broke my phone.
终结者把我的手机终结了
Excuse me.
失陪下
Okay, I'll be honest with you.
好了 实话跟你说吧
I've just spent the last two hours
imagining various scenarios in my head,
两个小时了 我脑子里构想了无数场景
trying to come up with some
clever line to say to you.
想找点啥机智的台词跟你说说
But then I finally realized you're
a human being; I'm a human being.
但我意识到你是人 我也是人
- I could just say to you...
- Next stop: Santa Barbara.
- 我可以干脆跟你说...
- 下一站 圣巴巴拉
I'm sorry. This is me.
抱歉 我到站了
Hi, my name's Leonard.
嗨 我叫Leonard
So, I'm thinking, you won the
Nobel Prize what, three years ago?
于是我就想 你是啥时候
3年前得的诺贝尔奖?
So you must deal with a whole lot
of "What has Smoot done lately?"
肯定回应了不少
"Smoot最近有啥成就"之类问题
My thought is we continue
my research as aeam--
我想着咱们组队继续我的研究
you know, Cooper-Smoot,
alphabetical--
那个 叫Cooper-Smoot 字母顺序
and when we win the Nobel
Prize, you'll be back on top.
等我们赢了诺贝尔
你又可以重回巅峰了
With all due respect, Dr.
Cooper, are you on crack?
恕我直言 Cooper博士 你嗑药了吧?
Fine! Smoot-Cooper.
好了啦! Smoot-Cooper
Wow, what a diva.
哦哟 瞧这架子